[electrical crackling]
[electronic pulsing]
Okay, let's see
what we got here.
Seen it. Seen it.
Huh. What's this about?
At the dawn...
dawn... dawn...
dawn... dawn... dawn...
[electronic speech echoing]
[beeps, whirs]
[echoing continues, stops]
[blows]
Ah. Here we go.
[deep voice]
At the dawn of time,
there was our gracious
and powerful creator,
Primus.
To protect our universe,
he sacrificed his life force,
transforming himself
into our planet,
Cybertron.
From within Cybertron's core,
Primus birthed
the first Transformers
known as the Primes,
the most powerful
Transformers,
appointed to lead and protect
future generations.
To assist them, Primus created
an entity of great power,
the Matrix of Leadership.
The Matrix, there it is. Okay.
Good. Come on. Keep going.
[deep voice] With the Matrix
in the Primes' possession,
Cybertron's natural
power source, Energon,
flowed in abundance,
sustaining life
across the planet.
[electronic voice] Attention!
Unauthorized movement
detected in archival vault.
Sector J-3.
[sentry] KDQ-12 to KDK-1.
Breaching archives
in ten seconds.
[deep voice] For generations,
there was peace and prosperity,
until the Matrix
of Leadership was lost,
causing Energon
to no longer flow.
[groans] Why does every legend
about the Matrix
end right there?
[sighs] One of these
has to say what happened.
[electronic voice]
Halt, criminal!
Prepare to be detained!
Oh, hey there.
Halt, criminal!
Prepare to--
[electrical sputtering]
[alarm blares]
Uh-oh.
Freeze!
Get down!
Well, hello, guys.
I'm so glad you're here.
Which way is the exit?
[chuckles]
I must've taken a wrong turn.
It's that defective mining bot,
Oreon Pix!
Orion Pax.
Who cares?
We told you
to never come back here!
Why are we all yelling?
I'm gonna smash you!
Hold on.
Whoa, whoa, hold on.
No need for violence.
How about this:
I run away, you chase me.
We play that game. Huh?
Come on.
You're bigger, faster.
It'll be fun.
He doesn't have a cog.
Let's give him a head start.
Why not?
It's not like
he can transform.
Oh, yeah?
Well, watch this.
[wondrous music begins]
[music abruptly stops]
Get him!
[grunts]
I-- I-- Uh...
Something that flies.
[electronic voice]
Prepare to be detained!
Halt, criminal!
[electronic whirring]
[grunts, yells]
Come on! Start! Come on!
Whoa!
[indistinct electronic speech]
[grunts]
Whoa. No, no, no, no! [yells]
There he is!
[grunts]
Ha-ha! So long, suck--
[overlapping chatter]
Ooh, Energon.
Evening, everyone.
Pardon me.
[grunts] Hey!
[laughs]
Whoa!
Ah, it's Orion.
Seriously, again?
[chuckling] Okay, fellas!
Thanks for the head start.
You want to give me
another one?
You're dead!
I'll take that as a no.
[grunts] Hey!
Watch where you're going!
Oh...
What did you say, no-cog?
Sorry, sir,
I didn't mean you.
I was referring
to the bot
who was behind you.
What? Where'd he go?
The filthy
red and blue bot?
Has a big mouth,
squeaky joints,
gives off a corroded
metallic stench?
Where is he?
He went that way.
When I get
my hands on that bot...
All right, all clear.
Okay, D-16,
I may be a little rusty,
but "corroded"?
That is too far.
Let me guess.
Chased out of
the archives?
[laughs] Yeah.
I had to jump
out of a window this time.
Almost died.
[laughs] It was wild.
And digging through
ancient data
is worth dying for?
Yes, it is.
I need a new best friend.
If there are clues
in our recorded history
that can help locate
the Matrix of Leadership,
they're in the archives.
Sentinel Prime,
the Sentinel Prime,
is up on the surface
right now,
risking his life for us
in search of the Matrix.
That's exactly what I'm doing.
I'm trying to help him.
Yeah, okay. [laughs]
The sooner Energon
flows again,
the sooner we won't
have to mine for it.
Don't you want
to choose your own path,
do whatever you want?
We're miners.
We mine, that's all.
No, there has got to be
something more I can do.
I can feel it.
Oh, yeah? Like the time
you had a "feeling"
you could transform
without a cog?
You said you were never
gonna mention that again.
Took me three days
to pry you open.
Your feelings
get you in trouble.
Yeah, yeah.
Just trust
in Sentinel Prime.
I do trust in him.
Hey, if we did have cogs--
I'd transform
into a shovel
and beat you.
I don't like how fast
you answered that.
But listen, if you did beat me,
I couldn't give you this awesome
Megatronus Prime thing
I have here. It's cool.
I'll give it
to someone else.
What Megatronus Prime thing?
Ah, it's nothing.
Just a, you know,
mint-condition Megatronus Prime
decal, first edition.
[gasps] What?
If you don't want it,
I can just throw it away.
Throw it away? Don't--
That's not funny.
Let me see.
Wait. Don't grab.
You're gonna crease it.
You know, Sentinel says
Megatronus was the--
The strongest Prime
to ever live.
I know, buddy.
Looks good on you.
Ah, it's really cool.
Thanks.
Always got your back.
No matter what.
[electronic voice]
Approaching sublevel station.
Stand clear of doors.
Mining teams,
prepare to unload.
[electrical whirring, crackling]
Metal to the pedal, drill bits.
This is it.
How much Energon have you mined
under my leadership?
[all] So much, Elita-1!
And how perfect
is my mining record?
[all] So perfect, Elita-1!
We are a mere
30 units of Energon away
from my promotion to supervisor.
Are you happy for me?
[all] So happy, Elita-1!
[Orion] Elita-- I mean Captain,
you are looking especially shiny
this morning. New polish?
Orion Pax,
I'm sorry that I somehow
gave you the impression
that we're friends.
Apology accepted.
Light up that wall!
Let's go! Ten seconds!
Happy to take
the lead today, Captain.
Feeling like I have
enough power in me
to drill down
and touch Primus myself.
You don't have
the touch or the power.
Ready positions,
rust buckets! Let's go!
She's in a good mood today.
Mm-hmm.
You ready?
Always ready.
Let's punch in.
[Elita] Here we go.
This one won't be open long.
Brace it up!
Here we go! Bridge!
[miner] Brace up!
Lower channel is open.
[crackling]
[whirring]
[miner 2]
Drill power on max!
[tools whirring]
[miner 3] Low bridge!
Drill it out!
I tapped a vein!
[sputtering, metallic thud]
[metallic groaning]
It's unstable!
We got to go, we got to move!
[electronic pulse]
[all yelling]
[roar building]
Evacuate!
[all yelling]
Everyone out!
Evacuate immediately!
The tunnel is closing.
I repeat, the tunnel is closing!
You with me, D?
[D-16] On your six! Keep going!
Look out!
[electrical whirring,
sputtering]
[pained groan]
Jazz is stuck!
Elita, we've got
a trapped miner.
I'm falling back to assist.
[Elita] Negative.
Do not break protocol.
Evacuate!
We're gonna need more lift.
It's closing!
Just grab your pack and go.
Yeah. Good idea.
What? No, I didn't mean it!
[grunts]
[electronic whirring]
Pull him clear!
[groans, yells]
[Elita] Pax, what's happening?
Nothing much. Just normal
protocol-following stuff.
It's all good.
[deep rumbling]
Oh, that's not good.
[rumbling swells]
Orion Pax, could you please exit
the tunnel of death?
[Orion] Elita, it's about
to get messy out there!
[electronic pulse]
[all grunting]
Go, go, go!
[mechanical whirring]
Run! Run!
Hurry!
We're not gonna make it!
Come on! Go, go, go!
[all yelling]
[electrical sputtering]
What the hell, Pax?
I told you to evacuate.
I did, eventually.
If I get fired because of you--
Oh, please.
They're not
gonna fire you.
Elita-1, you're fired.
What? Why? I followed
protocol to the letter.
That is true.
I was the one
who broke the rules.
No one asked you!
Darkwing, please,
I've worked too hard
for this.
You are no-cog bots
with limited options.
Report to waste management
immediately.
Waste management?
Elita...
Next time,
why don't you stop and think
before you ruin someone's life?
I'm sorry!
[indistinct chatter]
Hey, Darkwing!
Don't do it.
I may not have a cog,
but my finger can transform.
Guess which one?
I'll give you
a "limited option."
[imitates mechanical creak]
[growls]
Excuse me, sir.
Allow me.
[grunts]
I apologize
on his behalf for the--
[slow groan] Why?
[D-16] That really hurt. [sighs]
What'd you expect?
He's metal.
You know you were
out of line,
talking back
to a superior like that.
Darkwing was out of line.
He deserves it.
[sighs]
Aren't you tired of being
treated like we're nothing?
He had every right
to hit me.
I interfered.
Hey, and I appreciate
you having my back.
I'm glad
you were there with me
to get punched in the face.
That was fun.
[laughs]
Anytime, buddy.
[electronic tones]
[electronic voice]
Attention, all sectors.
Stand by for
a live transmission
from Sentinel Prime.
He's back?
He's back already?
Maybe he found the Matrix.
[chatter]
[electronic whirring]
Is it on? Okay, thank you.
Hello, my friends.
Hello, Iacon City!
Hello to our saviors,
the industrious miners
who toil selflessly to maintain
our Energon reserves.
I celebrate you.
[crowd cheering]
Humility and presence!
That's leadership!
Ah! Nobody does it better!
Once again, I have narrowly
returned with my fleet
after another
treacherous expedition
across the desolate, dangerous
surface of our planet.
I departed with hopes
of finding
the Matrix of Leadership,
the key to bringing balance
to Cybertron.
I regret to inform you
that we've
returned empty-handed.
[disappointed groans]
This is a setback,
but not a failure.
Rest assured, I will find
the Matrix of Leadership,
so that Energon can flow again.
But that's in the future.
Right now,
I think we all
deserve a little fun!
Tomorrow,
there will be no work.
All shifts off
because tomorrow
is the Iacon 5000!
[raucous cheers]
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
My favorite event.
A high-octane race
all across Iacon City.
Let's all see which competitor
can prove they are truly
more than meets the eye.
[cheering continues]
[laughs excitedly]
[Orion whispering] D.
Psst! Hey, D.
[groans groggily]
Oh, good, you're up.
Come on, I have an idea.
[D-16] Whatever this is,
it better be good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. Listen.
All right, what if...
what if...
what if tomorrow
we ran
in the Iacon 5000, huh?
What if kill you
for waking me up?
No, no, no, hear me out.
We don't even have to win!
Oh, that's good,
because we wouldn't.
But-- But if we beat
just one Transformer,
it proves
we're just as good as they are.
Not only would we
go down in history,
the mining bots
that did the impossible,
but we would show everyone
that we're--
we're capable
of so much more!
Or we get
publicly humiliated
and then busted
back to tier one.
Yeah, but at least we would've
done something, you know?
Pax...
Come on, D.
Pax.
We're mining bots
who can't transform.
We can't fly,
we can't roll,
we can't race.
Come on, let's go.
[sighs]
All right, fine.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
Maybe.
[D-16] The Iacon 5000
is finally here!
[Orion] I have a surprise
for you. Come on.
Where are you going?
The stadium's that way.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Follow me.
Great.
We're gonna be late now.
I wanted good seats.
We came all this way to miss
the opening ceremony.
This is wonderful!
Trust me,
I know what I'm doing.
Hold up!
[electronic pulse]
[groans, sighs]
Get caught in one of those,
it'll launch you
halfway across the city.
Okay,
where are you taking me?
[mechanical whirring]
Don't be a glitch, this will be
totally worth it. Trust me.
Hey, you don't be a glitch.
Look, I know this is, like,
fun for you,
like, we're joking around,
but if you make me miss
any part of the Iacon 5000,
I swear I will smelt
your face right off your...
[announcer]
Welcome to the Iacon 5000.
There they are.
Put your hands together
as today's competitors
are taking the field.
[D-16] Look! There's
Thunderglide and Behemoth!
This is unbelievable!
I feel like I'm in the race!
You did this for me?
No.
I did this for us.
[announcer] And now the moment
you've all been waiting for.
The icon of Iacon!
The savior of Cybertron!
Quintessons fear him,
but we love him!
Our leader,
the one and only...
Sentinel Prime!
[cheers, applause]
I love you, Sentinel!
Yes! It feels so good
to be here with you all today.
[raucous cheers]
My friends.
My Cybertronian family.
[crowd quiets]
It has been
precisely 50 cycles
since the Quintessons
attacked our home.
Fifty cycles since we lost
the Matrix of Leadership
and our Energon supply
dried up.
Fifty cycles since the battle
that killed the other Primes,
my brothers
and sisters in arms.
Today we honor the Primes
who gave their lives for ours
and we show them
that the strength of Cybertron
will never be diminished.
Racers, on your marks!
[cheers, applause]
[mechanical whirring]
I can't believe we get to watch
from the starting line.
The best seats
in the house!
[beeps, whirs]
Why'd you bring jetpacks?
[announcer] Get set!
It's time to show them
we are more than meets the eye.
Oh, no.
[electronic pulse]
[announcer] And they're off!
[yelps, grunts]
[grunts, yells]
Are you crazy?
Sure feels like it.
[announcer]
The Iacon 5000 has begun!
I'm sorry, are those
miners in the race?
Miners!
Those are miners,
like us!
[announcer] I can't believe
what I'm seeing here!
Miners trying to run
in the Iacon 5000!
You've got to be kidding me.
[announcer] This is insane!
There are miners
in the race!
Miners?
No way!
They can't even transform!
It's Orion Pax and D-16!
[announcer] This is a first
in Iacon 5000 history.
How are they going to survive?
[electronic pulsing, zipping]
If we survive this,
I'm gonna kill you!
I accept those terms.
[announcer] It's Tailwind
pulling into the lead
down the main stretch
followed by Strafe and Skyfire!
[electronic pulse]
[yelps]
[D-16] Hey, look out! [grunts]
I owe you one.
More like a thousand.
I can't believe
we're not in last place!
[D-16 screams]
[mechanical whirring]
[Darkwing] Eat it, miner!
[announcer] Darkwing delivers
a devastating blow!
[Orion] Gotcha!
We're not fast enough!
Improvise!
[Spinout] Hey! Get off!
[D-16] Spinout! Big fan!
[Jetstorm] Hey!
[D-16] Jetstorm, I'm so sorry.
Big fan! [yells]
Get off!
[grunts]
[laughs]
Time it just right!
And... now!
[grunts]
Move!
[pained yell]
[announcer] And the miners
have fallen way behind.
We can now focus
on the real contenders
in this race.
[panting]
[mechanical swell]
[electronic pulse]
[both yelling]
[Darkwing grunts]
[announcer] I don't believe it!
The miners take down Darkwing!
Oh, miners!
Great effort,
Darkwing!
That worked!
It actually worked!
Is this the dumbest thing
we've ever done?
Oh, yeah, it's up there!
[mechanical whirring]
[screams]
[grunts]
No, no, no!
Whoa!
[grunts, yelps]
Wait!
Go, go, go!
[announcer] A four-bot pileup
in the magnetic tunnel
and the two miners are now
in first position!
[cheers, applause]
This is unbelievable!
Ah!
[crowd gasps]
D!
No. Go. Leave me!
No, we do this together.
[announcer] One miner is now
carrying the other
mere steps
from the finish line
in the most amazing,
sensational, dramatic,
heartrending, exciting,
thrilling finish
in the history of--
[both grunt]
We have a winner!
Chromia comes from behind
to take the prize.
Talk about an Iacon 5000
for the ages.
[both panting]
Well, second place
is still pretty good.
[electronic whooshing]
[intercom voice]
Paging Dr. Ratchet.
Dr. Ratchet to Medical Bay 94.
Do not worry.
You will be fixed up
in no time.
[pained groan] Did I win?
You participated.
[wounded bot] Yay!
So...
how long do you think
we'll be here?
I'm not talking to you.
You know what?
I can't believe
you made me do that.
We are so screwed!
Thought you weren't
talking to me.
Hey, look, I know
it's all a big joke to you.
But not me.
I was paying my dues.
I was going places.
And now they're gonna
bust me down
I-- I don't even know
how many tiers!
I'm sorry, D.
But come on,
didn't you feel it?
Even for just a second,
didn't you feel liberated?
Didn't you feel like
you were something else?
Like you could be more
than what they say you are?
Yeah, I felt it. I did.
But it doesn't matter.
We're going to get
punished and demoted.
[sighs] Sentinel Prime
saw the whole thing.
This is so embarrassing.
[metallic clanking]
[electronic beeping, whirring]
It's clear.
Orion Pax.
D-16.
What you two did today
was one of the
craziest things
I've ever seen.
Sir, this is all my idea,
and we're so sorry.
I loved it!
You did?
How could anyone
not love it?
You gave my best racers
a real run for their money.
So we're not
getting demoted?
Demoted?
[laughing]
[both laughing nervously]
Demoted.
[laughter continues]
What is happening?
[laughs awkwardly]
The fact of the matter
is we're halfway
into the first shift
since the race ended
and that mining crew
has already reached 150% quota.
You inspired them
to work harder!
Sentinel Prime, sir,
we joined the race
to show everyone our potential.
That we bots can do
more than just mine--
Outstanding! I love a bot
that can think for himself.
Perhaps you two
could tour the mines,
speak to your brethren, and
help them see their potential.
[laughs] Wow! Okay, great.
[stammering]
That sounds incredible.
I would love to--
Sir, it's time.
Ah, yes.
I'm sorry, friends.
We're preparing
our next travel
to the surface.
But in the meantime,
I've got a treat for you.
Hang tight.
Airachnid, have someone
escort these heroes
to my personal
service facilities.
Best care in Iacon.
Until next time, legends.
Sentinel Prime. [laughs]
The Sentinel Prime!
You still mad at me?
I am less mad at you.
I'm telling you, D--
I got a feeling
that everything's gonna change
and we're gonna go--
[heavy footsteps]
[growling] Miners!
Hi, Darkwing.
[Orion] Oh, no, no, no.
[D-16] No! [yells]
Wait, wait!
You don't understand!
We were supposed to go
to Sentinel Prime's service pod!
You two dolts aren't going
to see anyone ever again.
I'll make sure of that.
You're making a mistake!
Ask Sentinel!
[groans]
I hate that guy!
[clattering]
[clattering continues]
You! How did you get down here?
There's no access to this level.
There is nobody
down here but me.
[stammers indistinctly]
Oh, my gosh, you're real!
You're others!
You're not... me!
You're here,
and you're not me!
[laughs]
Uh, yeah.
Awesome!
I am so sorry. That must
have been weird for you.
I just haven't had
a lot of company
since they put me
down here in sublevel 50.
Fifty? But there
are only 40 sublevels.
That's what I thought!
Turns out there are ten more,
and they are not pleasant.
Probably why nobody ever
really talks about them.
How long have you
been down here?
How long have I been here?
[laughs]
Let's see, somewhere
between a long time and forever?
I mean, I had other jobs,
but I kept getting reassigned
'cause I'm so good
at what I do.
Oh! I'm B-127, by the way.
But you can call me B.
And I'm actually
working on some nicknames.
The one I'm floating right now
is Badassatron.
Which is actually pronounced...
[deep voice] "Badassatron."
But if you have any critiques--
Yeah, great.
How do we get
out of here?
Great question. You don't.
We don't?
Nope.
We have limited access
to the waste management area,
but the new shift manager there
does not like distractions.
No, they prefer we stay here
on the task at hand.
Which is?
Oh!
The scrap comes in
from the chute there
onto the conveyor belt.
Our job is to look for anything
that might be worth salvaging
before it hits the furnace
and gets smelted.
So you watch garbage burn.
Yes!
It is so great
that you're here now.
I can't wait to learn
everything about you.
And then tell you
everything about me!
I have a lot of hopes and dreams
that I am just dying to share
with one or two
new best friends.
Uh, yeah, I would love to--
[splutters]
Where are my manners?
Come on, I'll introduce you
to the rest of the crew.
Hey, guys, we've got company!
This is EP-508,
this is A-A-Tron,
and this fella here is Steve.
"Steve"?
Yeah, he's foreign.
Question:
Do they talk back to you?
Um, they're not real.
[laughing]
Jeez, you think I'm that crazy?
It's just
you've been down here a--
No, I was talking to Steve.
[beeps and whirs]
[indistinct robotic speech]
[laughs]
Classic Steve.
What is that?
Look at this guy.
[mocks electronic speech]
It's coming from inside.
Oh! Steve! No!
I am so sorry.
[dramatically] Steve, no!
We can fix it, don't worry.
My Steve!
[voice over transmission]
Quintesson ambush!
Calling the High Guard
for immediate support.
Immediate support!
That's Alpha Trion.
One of the Primes?
Repeat,
Zeta Prime has fallen!
It's an SOS message.
Protect the Matrix!
Sending location coordinates.
Holy Primus!
Those are coordinates
to a location on the surface.
This could be
where the Primes died
in the Quintesson war.
Which means
this is where we could find
the Matrix of Leadership.
What are you talking about?
It's an old beacon
inside a statue made of garbage.
Or it's a clue
of how we could find
the Matrix of Leadership.
No. No way. Absolutely not!
Hey, D, come on,
this could be our chance
to show everyone we're not--
You already tried
to "show everyone"
in the race
you tricked me
into running,
which got us
stuck down here
in this waste hole
with this, uh...
really cool guy.
Oh, thank you.
I'm just saying--
There's a reason
no one goes
to the surface.
It's dangerous!
I'm waiting right here
until Sentinel Prime
finds us.
Oh, okay. Yeah. Hmm.
Well, we'll just
stay here forever.
That cool with you, B?
Forever? This is great!
I have new coworkers
and roommates.
There's plenty of room
now that Steve is dead.
I usually sleep
on the conveyor belt,
but you can totally have it.
I'll sleep in the corner
next to A-A-Tron.
Plenty of room
for you to stretch out, too,
'cause you're taller than I am.
Know what I mean?
Hey, D, what do you think
Sentinel's reaction would be
if you personally handed him
the Matrix of Leadership
that you found?
Okay, stop.
I know what you're
trying to do.
And it's
definitely working.
I'm in.
Hah, ha! Yeah, buddy.
How do we get
to the surface?
Pfft! You kidding me?
The surface?
Easy. I know a way.
But it won't be easy.
[D-16]
Why is there so much trash? Ah!
[Orion] Warn me
next time, please.
My mouth was open.
[B-127] Only 49 sublevels to go!
Waste-disposal trains
are the only vehicles
that go all the way
to the surface.
[D-16] Yeah, but they
don't allow passengers.
The trains are autonomous.
Yeah, that's the
"won't be easy" part.
It's perfect.
We'll be safe
inside the train.
[worker] That's the last one.
Send 'er up!
[door whirs, thuds]
[Elita] Hold up! One more.
I'll lock it down.
[electronic beeps, clicks]
[laughs]
Thanks for being an idiot,
whoever you are.
Turning you in will
definitely get me promoted
back up a rank or two.
Got her!
[grunting]
No, wait, I--
Elita! Stop!
Orion?
Hold on, let me--
Security! Sound the ala--
[grunts angrily]
She's headed to the engine!
Don't worry, I got this.
Hold on, let me explain!
We're on a mission!
So am I. To ruin your life.
[yells]
[all grunt]
Elita, wait. We found a message.
We know where--
This bot is crazy! Who is she?
Dead end, Elita.
There's no way...
Well, she's gone.
[all grunting]
[groans]
Whoa!
Why? Why am I doing this?
Why am I doing this?
Climb faster!
[all groaning]
Gotcha!
[grunts]
Ah, the surface.
It's beautiful.
[B-127] I am speechless.
Elita, listen to me.
We know where
the Matrix of Leadership is.
Oh, sure.
And I'm really a Prime.
I just prefer loading
crates of toxic waste.
Whoa.
Where did you get this?
From my friend Steve.
Orion killed him.
I did not kill Steve.
He was never alive.
What?
Look.
Sentinel told us
he was going to the surface,
and then we found this message.
We figured that we could
hand deliver it to him
or scout
the locations ourselves.
Whichever comes first.
This was too important to wait.
It will change all of our lives.
[inhales sharply]
No, no, no, no.
I'm not going to get demoted
again because of you.
I'm turning this rig around
and I'm notifying the--
[rumbling]
Hey, guys? Guys?
What is that?
[rumbling swells]
Is it getting bigger?
Or closer?
[alarm blares]
[rumbling intensifies]
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Are you closing?
Don't close. Stop closing.
It's closed!
[Elita] Oh, come on!
[rumbling, alarm continue]
Oh, now I know why
no one comes to the surface!
[mechanical whirring]
[grunts]
[all exclaiming]
[all yelling]
[yelling reverberates]
[Orion] Elita?
[wind blowing]
Elita?
[Elita groans]
You okay?
[grunts]
Please stop
punching me in the face.
[B-127, distant]
Can you help?
Iacon-- The train--
Where's the train?
Relax, okay? Here it comes.
And there it goes.
Okay, I was wrong about that.
It was going the other way.
[Elita screams]
[scream echoing]
[grunting]
Okay, so I think
this is us,
and if we follow
the path to--
Now you listen to me,
Mr. "Zero Seconds
Since My Last Accident"!
I'll go on your little quest
because I don't have a choice.
But I carry the map, I navigate,
and if this leads to nothing,
then I'm dragging you
and those two idiot go-bots
back to Iacon City
and to the first
supervisor depot we see,
at which point you will explain
everything that's happened,
using words that reflect me
in a very positive light!
Got it?
Yeah, okay.
Deal. Great. All right.
Let's go!
She's joining us?
[laughs eagerly]
Fantastic!
Hi there. Uh, Elita, right?
Am I saying that right?
Wanted to formally
introduce myself.
I'm B-127. You kneed me
in the face earlier, back there.
You can call me B,
or Badassatron.
It's a nickname
some of the guys gave me.
I don't know. I didn't give it
to myself or anything.
Actually, it's pronounced...
[deep voice] "Badassatron,"
in case you were wondering.
[deep voice] Badassatron.
You like that, right?
[deep voice] Badass--
I'm gonna need you
to talk less.
Sure! No-- Yeah, no problem.
What am I talking less about,
my nickname?
That's fine with me.
Got some mountains over here...
Hey. You're thinking
about what you'll say
when you hand the Matrix
to Sentinel, aren't you?
I can't help it.
D, we're really doing this.
So glad
I'm out here with you.
This was a great idea.
[B-127]
I'm just having a good time.
How much further
is the Matrix on the map?
Make an educated guesstimate.
This is the coolest thing
that has ever happened
to anyone anywhere,
I'm telling you!
[B-127] ♪ Not one, not two
Not three, but four ♪
♪ Four best friends who are
Walking through the door ♪
There's no doors,
we're outside.
Hey, look,
there's more of it over here.
What is it?
It's not metal.
It's like some kind
of weird nature. It's weird.
So are they.
[B-127]
♪ Going to the Matrix ♪
♪ With my best friends ♪
[deep rumble]
What was that?
[electronic blips]
[wind blowing]
[light metallic clinking]
Um...
I think this is not right.
We should go.
Yeah, good idea.
Run!
[all panting]
What are we running from?
[rumbling]
[all panting]
[rumbling, clattering]
[mechanical warbling]
[D-16] What is that?
[Orion] Oh, no.
It's a Quintesson ship.
[Elita] What?
What do we do?
Shh! Quiet.
[rapid metallic footsteps]
[all gasping]
[electronic whirring, pulsing]
It's scanning for life-forms.
Move, move!
[whirring]
Wait! [gasping]
[panting]
Go, go, go, go!
[grunts]
Come on!
They're not gonna make it.
[straining]
Whoa.
[grunts, exhales]
What-- What were they
searching for?
Someone to hug, B.
How should I know?
I'm not waiting around
to find out.
This way.
We're close.
[Orion] Quintessons haven't
been here for 50 cycles.
[Elita] It doesn't make sense.
There's nothing out here.
A cave with teeth.
Nothing scary about that.
[B-127] Knives coming
out of the ceiling. Amazing.
Everyone,
do we have to go insi--?
[electronic blips]
Okay, yep, we're going in.
Why shouldn't we? Just walking
into the scariest place
I've ever seen
in my entire life.
This is ridiculous.
I don't believe it.
[Orion] The Primes.
[Elita] We're here.
Megatronus Prime.
Zeta Prime.
The Matrix!
It's gone.
Let's keep looking.
Hey, guys!
It's Alpha Trion!
[Orion] He's powered down.
But his spark is still lit.
[electrical crackling]
Quintesson ambush!
Attack!
[groans]
Message before--
Whoa, whoa, it's okay!
It's okay.
You're safe now.
The war is over.
[sighs, grunts softly]
[weak mechanical whirs]
[grunts weakly]
I failed you, old friend.
You deserved
so much better than this end.
No, you didn't fail.
We heard your message.
We've come to find
the Matrix.
Your transformation cogs.
What happened to you?
Who are you?
We're cogless miners,
from Iacon.
Miners? Why?
Well, we've had
to drill for Energon
ever since
it stopped flowing.
Impossible.
That's why we came.
To fix things.
If we find
the Matrix of Leadership
and get it to Sentinel Prime,
he can fix--
Sentinel is no Prime.
What?
He's broken.
Fantastic.
What are you talking about?
Why would you say that?
Sentinel Prime
is our protector.
He's been saving us from
the Quintessons ever since--
You have not been saved.
You've been living a lie.
I saw the truth
with my own eyes.
Come. I will show you.
[heavy footsteps]
For thousands of cycles,
the war with the Quintessons
had been a brutal conflict.
Until Sentinel,
the principal aide
to the Primes,
intercepted an enemy transmission.
There was going to be
a secret gathering
of Quintesson commanders.
Their elimination
could end the war.
It was a mission so important,
we Primes took it on ourselves.
We agreed to meet Sentinel for
his sensitive intel in secret,
here in this cave.
But we were not alone.
[chittering]
[Prime] Quintessons!
[Prime 2] They're here!
[Prime 3] It's a trap!
Battle positions!
Hold the line!
[Prime] Primus be with us!
[laserfire pulsing]
For Cybertron!
[Alpha Trion]
We were outnumbered,
but stood as one.
Our victory was near.
Until we were betrayed.
[metallic slice]
[grunts]
[pained yell]
[audio slows]
[grunting]
Sentinel, why?
For all the power
of Cybertron.
[Alpha Trion] But Sentinel never
understood the true power
of what he desired.
The Matrix of Leadership
can only be wielded
by one that Primus himself
deems worthy.
And Sentinel
most certainly was not.
No!
Wait. Hold on. You're saying
that the Matrix of Leadership
just vanished?
No.
No, no, no. That is impossible.
I don't believe it.
Why would Sentinel
do that?
To make a bargain.
A bargain? With who?
[deep rumbling]
With the new rulers
of Cybertron.
[Orion] The Quintessons.
[Elita] There are so many.
[electronic whirring]
He's here.
Sentinel Prime is here.
[warbling]
[chittering]
Keep your eyes open.
They always are.
[gasping]
[guttural chittering]
[Elita] I load those crates.
Those are filled
with contaminated metal.
I don't understand.
What do the Quintessons
want with toxic waste?
Our Energon.
Traitor!
D, no.
[grunts, groans]
[straining]
I know what
I promised you
but our mines,
they're running out!
There's barely
enough Energon for us.
[roars]
I swear I will
get you the rest.
Triple-time
every mining shift.
No miner gets a break
until I get my Energon.
All of it! Let's go.
[ship rumbling]
Now you have seen the truth.
Every day...
Every single day
of my life
has been a lie.
My God, I knew it!
Deep down,
I always felt
something was off.
He deceived everyone.
Sentinel bought himself power
and then put us to work
paying off his debt.
I can't believe it.
Well, obviously,
I can believe it,
I just saw it,
but I still...
I can't believe it.
Sentinel lied
to my face.
[Orion]
It was all a sham.
How could we
have been so gullible?
Oh, this-- this is going
to change everything.
[thudding]
[grunting]
You just had to do it,
didn't you?
Me? What did I do?
You just had
to go to the surface,
had to enter the Iacon 5000.
You just had to break protocol!
Who cares about protocol?
I do!
I care!
Because nothing bad happens
when you stay on protocol!
Sentinel Prime
has been forcing us
to work in the mines
until our gears strip,
and all the while he's been
giving the Energon away
to our greatest enemies!
And what do you think
he's going to do to us
when he finds out that we know?
I'm not thinking about
what he's going to do,
I'm thinking about
what we're going to do.
That's the whole thing!
You're never thinking about
anything else, just yourself!
Fantastic!
Another Orion Pax master plan.
I can't wait to hear this.
Don't you want
to stop him?
No, I want to kill him!
I want to put Sentinel in chains
and march him
through the mines
so everyone can see him
for the false Prime that he is!
I want him to suffer
and then to die in darkness.
But we all know
that it doesn't matter
what I want, right, Pax?
The fact is,
we're just cogless bots. Right?
[D-16 chuckles bitterly]
We had limited options,
and now... now we have none.
No son or daughter of Cybertron
is born without a cog.
Oh, yeah.
I've been with myself
since I came online,
and this slot's
always been empty.
What are you saying?
Are you saying--
No. No way.
Nobody could be that evil,
not even Sentinel.
He removed your cogs
before you came online.
We were born with
transformation cogs,
but he...
He took them from us.
What defines a Transformer...
[grunts]
...is not the cog
in his chest
but the spark
that resides in their core.
A spark that gives you the will
to make your world better.
My fellow Primes had that spark.
And I see their strength
in you.
Take their cogs
and access
your full potential.
Prima.
Onyx.
Alchemist.
Micronus.
Warriors of noble spirit,
loyalty, strength.
Their uniqueness
enhanced by these.
[electronic whirring]
[electronic whirring continues]
They were one. You are one.
All are one!
Wait. We have...
You-- You gave us...
The ability
to change your world.
How you choose
to use that power
is up to you.
[laughs]
[heavy thud]
They've found us.
Oh, yes!
Time to fight back!
No. You must return to
Iacon City and alert everyone.
Embedded in this
are the records
I have shown you.
Use it to reveal the truth.
We will.
This tunnel leads
to the mountains.
Cybertron's future
is in your hands.
[thudding boom]
We're out of time.
We got to move!
Wait, we can't just
leave you here.
Your fight will come,
my friend.
Primus has a purpose
for us all.
But this fight...
[heavy booming thud]
This fight is mine.
Now go!
[thudding continues]
Stand down, old timer.
Ah. Old, you say?
[rumbling]
[laserfire pulsing]
[roars]
[electrical crackling]
[laserfire pulsing]
[roars]
Not too old for you.
[roaring]
We need to hurry!
I still think
we have better odds
fighting than outrunning them.
Wait! We have cogs.
We can transform now.
That's right.
Everyone ready?
I was born ready.
On three. One--
[all yelling]
[faint yelling, grunting]
Ah!
[laserfire pulsing]
[grunting]
How do we use these things?
I don't know. Just try.
[straining]
It's working. Ha! It's working!
My head! My head!
Whoa!
Help! Help!
This is not faster!
[yells, grunts]
Oh, come on!
And transform!
[yelling]
Wheels! I need wheels!
[laserfire pulsing]
[Elita yelling]
Whoa.
[audio slows]
[mechanical whirring]
[B-127 yelling]
Ha! [grunts]
[grunts, laughs]
Oh, wow.
We're alive!
I've never moved that fast.
That was incredible!
Did you see me slide all over?
[overlapping chatter]
[laser blast]
[engine humming]
[mechanical whirring]
Yes!
[laughing deliriously]
Hey, whoa, buddy.
You okay?
I'm great. Are you kidding me?
We can transform!
We transform!
Oh, hey! I know.
We're wasting time.
We have to get back to Iacon.
Looks like the fastest way
back to Iacon is--
Here, I got it.
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't worry, I got it.
Yeah, but be careful.
Our proof is inside and
you're spilling it everywhere.
I... got... it.
Okay.
Follow me.
[wheezes]
Alpha Trion!
You are still alive.
Would you look at that?
You look horrible.
Traitor.
You are a disgrace.
Primus will surely--
Uh-huh. Yes. Shut up.
I seized an opportunity
to take control of my future.
Anything to get
out of working for you
and that boring
council of elders.
Seriously,
I would watch you Primes
spend half the day
losing a war
and the other half
sitting around waxing poetic
about loyalty and honor.
And now look at you.
Hear my words:
You will fall.
And a new Prime will rise--
There you go again.
I don't want to listen
to any more speeches.
[groans]
There were others
in the cave with you.
Who are they?
They are to be your undoing.
You've lost, Sentinel.
Nothing you can do--
[pained grunt]
[electrical crackling]
[body thuds]
Oh, didn't I just say
no speeches?
You heard me, right?
This is what I'm talking about.
Unbelievable.
All of them are like that.
So disrespectful.
[sighs]
Okay. Hunt down the others.
With pleasure.
[engines humming]
Hey, buddy.
Oh. Hey.
You've been a little quiet.
Are you all right?
All I can think about
is Sentinel's smirking face.
He must pay for what he's done.
Someone has to do something.
We are. With Alpha's proof
inside that device,
we will show everyone the truth.
You honestly believe
it'll be that easy?
Iacon doesn't want
to hear the truth.
They worship Sentinel.
There's got to be
a better way
to bring him down.
We have to trust everyone will
believe what we show them.
I trusted Sentinel!
With everything.
I will never trust
a so-called leader ever again.
There's only one bot
I know I can trust--
[electrical crackling]
[grunting]
[electronic sputtering]
[voice] All right,
wake them up.
[gasps]
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
Now, are you spies
or just incompetent lackeys?
We're not spies.
But he is incompetent.
Scanning electrical impulses.
He speaks the truth.
That just means
he believes himself,
like any spy would.
[muffled indistinct speech]
Uh, why is he gagged?
He wouldn't stop talking.
[muffled speech continues]
Even when he was
unconscious?
Especially when
he was unconscious!
Enough!
Two options for you!
One, we slowly
dismantle each of you
one bolt and screw at a time,
and really make sure
you feel it.
Or two:
In exchange
for a quick death,
you give us intel
on the Energon trains,
access to the mines
or anything else that could
hurt your boss, Sentinel Prime.
Who exactly are you guys?
[muffled grunting, straining]
Ah!
The Cybertronian High Guard!
[growls] I told you
it wasn't tight enough!
Prestigious defenders
of Iacon.
Prestigious?
He's right.
I read all about you
in the archives.
You were
the most legendary warriors
in all of Cybertron.
Look, look, look!
That's Starscream,
and you're Shockwave,
and Soundwave.
Raise your hand
if "wave" is in your name.
There's a lot of "waves."
Silence!
The yellow annoying one
is correct.
Whoo!
We were once the High Guard.
We witnessed
Sentinel's betrayal,
saw the Primes fall.
Since that day, we've been
fighting from the shadows,
doing whatever we can
to sabotage Sentinel.
That's great! We're--
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay.
We're good.
Everyone relax.
I'm just saying we're allies.
We were on our way
back to Iacon,
and now with your help,
we can unify Cybertron
against Sentinel Prime.
The idea of a unified
Cybertron is a myth.
All that counts is the strength
of one bot over another!
[all cheering]
Okay. So, these guys
are a little intense.
Yeah. Just a little.
Hey!
What are you doing?
I tell you
what I'm not doing.
I'm not cowering
in some busted ship,
playing king of the throne.
I'm not pretending
like I'm making a difference
by throwing one punch
and then running away to hide!
I found out
that Sentinel is rotten today,
and I'm gonna
make him pay for it.
Today!
You think you can insult me
and just walk away?
No one leaves here
unless I say so.
[chuckles] Is that right?
Well, how can you say so
with my head in your teeth?
[grunts]
D!
[excited chatter]
[both grunting]
Whoa!
[grunting]
[mechanical whir]
[growls]
[grunts]
Hit me!
Do it! Come on! Yeah, more!
[crowd cheers]
[laughs]
[all] D-16! D-16! D-16!
You want to see the strength
of one bot over another? Huh?
[voice crackling] Is that
all you've got, tough bot?
Let's go! Do it! Come on!
[yells angrily]
[mechanical whirring]
[panting]
Please! I beg you!
Stop!
D, he's not the enemy!
Bear witness!
This is the last time
I show mercy!
Decide right now:
You can stay here in hiding,
bowing before
your pathetic leader,
or follow me
as we march on Iacon
and I take down Sentinel
once and for all!
[cheers, chanting]
[all] D-16! D-16! D-16!
[chanting fades]
[distant rumbling]
[all screaming]
[laserfire pulsing]
B, come on!
[B-127 yelling]
[mechanical whirring]
[grunts]
[Airachnid] Engage all hostiles!
I've got the bridge!
[grunts angrily]
[D-16 yelling]
[mechanical whirring]
[grunts]
Elita, get down!
[Orion coughs, clears throat]
I feel like someone
dropped a cliff on me.
[groans]
Where are the others?
Sentinel's troops
took as many prisoners
as they could carry.
They got D-16 and B.
Oh, no.
And half of those
High-Guard nutjobs.
[sighs]
Our proof.
It's gone.
So, what do we do now?
D was right.
About what?
Everything.
Look at it. Look around.
This is a disaster.
It's all my fault.
I should have
stayed on protocol.
[sighs]
Listen to me.
I really want you to hear this.
Are you listening?
I'm better than you.
Yeah, okay,
I'm hearing you.
I'm better than you
in every way,
except you have hope.
You always have. You went back
into the mine to rescue Jazz.
You snuck up
to the surface to find
the Matrix of Leadership.
[chuckles] Yeah,
and how'd that work out?
My point is,
that your instincts tell you
to break protocol for a reason.
This blind optimism
that you have
is why you make such bold
and courageous choices,
that are also extremely stupid.
First time
giving a pep talk?
You're inspiring.
You can envision a better future
that no one else can see.
And if we ever want to see
B and D-16 again,
that is the Orion Pax
that we need right now.
Listen to me.
We can do this.
Those Energon trains
will be heading
back to Iacon.
If we intercepted one--
Hell yes, I can reroute it.
What else do we need?
Well, my bold instincts tell me
we have to recruit some nutjobs.
I was afraid
you'd say that.
Uh, Shockwave, Soundwave.
You in the back.
In order to save
our captured friends,
we have to act now.
How about I blast you
back to Iacon?
[pained grunt]
Oh! She punched me in my eye!
Everyone, shut up!
All of you. Listen to him.
Most likely, our friends
are being held captive
at the top
of Sentinel's tower.
A surprise attack would
give us a chance to rescue them.
Impossible. We do not
have enough soldiers
or a way inside.
Elita will get us in.
And I will get more troops.
Why should we follow you?
We will follow you.
Attention, High Guard.
Prepare for battle.
What is our first move?
[quietly] We roll out.
What?
Louder.
[boldly]
Transform and roll out!
I don't understand.
Why are we still alive?
Look at this rowdy bunch!
The High Guard!
You know, you guys
have been tough to find.
Every trip to the surface,
I've been searching for you.
Tracking the bots in the cave
led me right to them.
Oh-ho-ho!
You captured Starscream!
It was too easy.
[high-pitch]
I'm going to rip you apart
piece by piece
so that your death
is painful!
[laughs]
You'll regret
the day you were--
You sound ridiculous.
It's weird.
Oh, D-16,
what a tragic story you'll be.
Atop the leaderboard
in your sector
and secretly a traitor.
I'm not a traitor.
You're the traitor.
Nuh-uh. You, all of you,
are traitors.
You've been working
with the Quintessons
to sabotage my expeditions.
You're the reason
why I haven't found
the Matrix of Leadership yet.
None of that is true!
Oh, trust me,
it'll be very true
when I'm executing you
in front of all of Iacon.
Because down here,
the truth is what I make it.
[thud reverberates]
Well, well.
What's this about?
I'm not kneeling
in front of you.
Feeling confident, are we?
You don't scare me.
You want to know why?
Please.
Because I don't have
anything left to lose.
You took it all.
I sure did.
[grunts]
[gasps]
[groans]
Ah, Megatronus Prime.
Of course you were a fan.
Megatronus was
the coolest Prime!
The biggest!
The baddest! The toughest!
That's why,
after I killed him,
I took his cog for myself.
He was greater
than you'll ever be!
I don't know. I'm pretty great.
But I can understand why you'd
want to wear his face over mine.
Here.
Let's make sure
it doesn't come off.
[electrical crackling]
[pained shouts, groans]
Okay. [sighs]
[stammers] I can do this.
[miner] You can't be serious.
We just worked
22 shifts without a break!
These miners need rest
and time to repair and--
Sentinel Prime
wants more Energon.
So get back in the mines
before I make you
get back in the--
[aggressive thud]
[triumphant electronic jingle]
Who was that?
Did you see
who that was?
[miner] That can't be him.
[Jazz] Is that...
It can't be.
Orion?
Jazz.
Is it really you?
Yeah, I know I, uh,
look a little different.
"Little"?
There's nothing
"little" about you.
Uh, how is this possible?
Sentinel told us you died
from your race injuries.
Sentinel is a liar.
What?
Huh?
Look, I know how this will sound
coming from me.
I was never
the most focused miner.
But as you can see,
everything is different now.
[mechanical whirring]
I went to the surface
and I learned the truth.
My friends,
we were all born
with transformation cogs.
And then Sentinel,
he stole them from us.
He took away our ability
to make our own decisions.
He stole our freedom.
But now, I'm offering you
your first real choice.
You can work a 23rd shift
and mine yourself to death
or fight back
against Sentinel with me.
Right now.
How are we supposed to do that?
We can't fight.
We don't have cogs.
What defines a Transformer
is not the cog in its chest
but the spark
that resides in their core.
A spark that gives you the will
to make your world better.
And that spark,
Sentinel can never
take from us.
There's not enough of us.
We'd need an army.
And we have one.
Elita is bringing troops.
We are not alone in this.
If we want to be in control
of our own destiny,
we will have to
fight for it.
Now is the time
for us to stand up...
[supportive chatter]
...for ourselves.
[scattered cheers]
Stand up for this injustice.
[cheers growing]
I promise you
this fight will be worth it.
Follow me.
Nothing can stop us
when we stand together.
[cheering, chanting]
Together as one.
[all chanting]
Orion Pax! Orion Pax! Orion Pax!
[Orion] Elita, it's time.
You got it.
Buckle up, Blinky.
We're going in.
[groaning, gasping]
[determined groans]
Not a good idea.
[whispering]
D, stay down.
[groans]
Well, that's a shame.
[mechanical whirs]
You really were
a great miner.
We've got a breach!
Protect Sentinel!
[grunts]
They spotted us.
It's about to get bumpy.
High Guard, eject.
Come on! Move out!
[laserfire pulsing]
[alarm blaring]
There's too many.
We have to abort!
[yelps]
[alarm intensifying]
We're not gonna make it.
[all yelling]
Whoo-hoo!
Metal to the pedal, miners!
Let's break some protocol!
[Elita] That's what
I'm talking about, Pax!
[growling]
[grunting]
Whoa! That's intense.
You can't win, miner.
I see everything!
That's right, you do.
Except the tower we're
about to crash into.
[alarmed chatter]
What's going on?
[electronic charge]
[Orion] Hey!
What has he done to you?
This is nothing compared to
what I'm gonna do to Sentinel.
[Orion] Soundwave,
free the prisoners.
[electronic throbbing]
I know how to stop him.
Airachnid is the answer.
I'm doing this my way.
D!
Yes!
Whoa!
[metal clangs]
Whoa-ho-ho!
I got a battle mask!
[grunts]
Elita! Battle mask!
It appeared
when this guy tried to--
Knife hands?
I have knife hands!
What the--?
[laughs triumphantly]
[deep voice] Badassatron.
Where's Sentinel?
[both grunt]
[Sentinel]
You pathetic little twits.
Did you really think
that you could knock down
everything I've built?
It's over, Sentinel.
You can't escape the truth.
[Sentinel] What truth?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
Forced you to mine
so that I could pay off
the Quintessons
and live like a king?
None of that matters!
Because the truth...
[mechanical whirring]
...is what I make it.
Incoming!
Whoa!
[laserfire pulses]
He's too strong.
I have a plan.
We need Airachnid.
Airachnid?
We need her memory.
Where is she?
Found her! [yells]
Elita!
Do not break her.
Bring her
to the broadcast station.
We'll meet you there.
[strained]
Easier said than done.
[yells]
[grunts]
[Orion] I said,
don't break her!
Relax! I'm being very gentle.
Orion! Orion, look!
I have knife hands!
I can see that.
I'm gonna cut these guys.
Watch. Come here!
You can jab them later.
We got to go.
[B-127] Yeah!
[laserfire pulsing]
[mechanical whirs]
[D-16 yells]
[roars]
Uh, excuse me.
You can't be in here.
B!
These are not
the bad guys.
Why did you cut the door?
What? No, I didn't--
That was an-- I--
It was already like that.
Right?
Yes, that's right.
That's right, yes.
Yeah, it was already like--
Yes. Mm-hmm.
[console beeps]
[female voice]
Attention, Iacon City.
Stand by for
a live transmission
from Sentinel Prime.
What's wrong, D-16?
Rise up!
[groans]
[Sentinel on recording]
That's why after I killed him--
That's why after I killed him,
I took his cog for myself.
...cog for myself.
What truth?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
Forced you to mine
so that I could pay off
the Quintessons
and live like a king?
What truth?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
Forced you to mine
so that I could pay off
the Quintessons
and live like a king?
I'm working my miners
as hard as I can.
I swear I will
get you the rest!
I'm working my miners
as hard as I can.
I swear I will
get you the rest!
[crowd gasps]
I'm working my miners
as hard as I can, I swear--
Liar!
[crowd protesting]
We trusted you!
Traitor!
Pax, we did it.
[roars]
[grunts heavily]
D!
[both grunting]
[panicked screams]
[grunts]
D-16.
We can lead Cybertron together!
Don't do this!
[weapon powering up]
[grunts]
[weapon powering down]
What are you doing?
It's over, D.
Everyone in Iacon
knows the truth.
So do I!
He took everything from us!
I have to do this!
No, you don't.
Rebuilding Iacon
cannot begin
with an execution.
He deserves to die!
Can't you see that?
We're better than this.
Don't be like Sentinel.
Pax,
you need to move
out of my way
before I move you myself.
D, listen--
[yells]
Stop!
[electronic pulse reverberates]
No!
No, no, no, no. Why?
Why did you do that? Why?
[wheezes, sighs]
[panting]
[slowed breaths]
[weakly] D, no.
I'm done saving you.
[straining grunt]
[roars]
[electrical crackling]
The Age of Primes has ended!
No more false prophets!
Follow me and you will
never again be deceived.
Rise up!
[crowd chanting]
Rise up! Rise up!
Rise up!
[Alpha Trion] Orion Pax,
your noble sacrifice
for the greater good
has proven you worthy
in the eyes of Primus.
He entrusts in you
the future of Cybertron
and the Matrix of Leadership!
[crowd clamoring]
I will lead us all
into the future!
[electrical crackling]
I...
am...
Megatron!
[Alpha Trion] Arise...
Optimus Prime.
Burn it down!
All of it!
All hail Megatron!
He's gonna kill everyone.
We have to stop him.
Come on.
Stop! It's over.
It's over when every last one
of his followers is dead!
[grunts]
Impossible.
Primus gave you the Matrix.
We could've built
the future together.
I'll build it myself.
After I tear down
everyone in my way!
[roars]
[pained grunt]
[electronic charging]
Ah!
[growling]
[both grunting]
[powering up]
[yells]
[roars]
[panting heavily]
We were given the power
to change our world
and you chose to destroy it.
Just like Sentinel.
You have betrayed Cybertron
and its citizens.
And you betrayed me.
Go.
Take the High Guard
and leave.
You are banished from Iacon.
It didn't have to end
this way.
This isn't over, Prime.
High Guard, follow me!
[Optimus Prime] The line
between friend and enemy
is not as clear
as I once believed.
Once it's crossed,
there's no going back.
Because some transformations
are permanent.
[Orion] Hey, Megatronus Prime.
Nice.
Oh, yeah.
Well, he's my hero.
[both] The greatest Prime
to ever live.
[both laugh]
I'm D-16.
Orion Pax.
You ever mine Energon before?
No. You?
No. I hear it's dangerous.
Well, I'll tell you what.
You watch my back,
I promise to watch yours.
All right.
Thanks, Pax.
A new beginning
for Cybertron.
And a new leader.
Yes, about that.
I could use some help
from a bot who is
better than me in every way.
Who, me? Oh, no, no.
I have a pretty sweet gig
working in waste management.
Well, Captain,
I do owe you a promotion.
How's Major Elita sound?
How about Commander?
[chuckles] Even better.
And I'm sorry, B,
but I cannot let you
go back to sublevel 50.
I may be a Prime now,
but I'm gonna need you
by my side.
Are you serious?
This is the greatest
day of my life.
I get to work
for the government.
[shimmering tone]
Okay. So that's new.
I'm sorry,
what is happening?
[all cheering]
[Optimus Prime]
And now we stand here
together as one...
proving we all have
the power to transform,
to become
who we were destined to be,
to right wrongs,
to make our world better.
Because here,
freedom and autonomy
are the rights
of all sentient beings.
Here,
all are truly Autobots.
This message is a warning
to all Quintessons.
If you dare
return to Cybertron,
the Autobots will be waiting.
I will be waiting.
I am Optimus Prime.
[door opens]
[rapid footsteps]
Hey, guys! Great news,
the Energon's back!
And I have a cog
and I can transform!
It's a long story.
I'll fill you in later.
Oh! And here's the best part.
My hands are straight-up knives.
Watch this. Knife hands!
No!
[Megatron]
Sentinel the betrayer is dead.
But his death has given life
to a new enemy.
A stronger enemy.
A personal enemy.
We will not be blinded
by his deception.
We are the ones who are...
Decepticons!
Rise up!
[all] Rise up! Rise up!
[crowd chanting]
[laserfire pulsing]
[chanting continues]